The most important thing you have to remember is that
every time you transfer data, no matter how small, the radio
could stay powered up for nearly half a minute. So every
decision you make will be based on minimizing the number of
times that this happens. But of course there's a balance here.
You want to download all the data a user is likely
to need for the current section in a single burst over
a single connection at full capacity. But of course, you don't
just want to pull down everything wasting battery power and bandwidth
downloading data that's never going to be used. Now I could go
on for hours on this topic, but Dan's getting impatient. And
you can learn the details on how to implement each of
these best practices, including pre-fetching,
batching and bundling, burying your
update frequency, and minimizing your payloads by watching the series of
Dev Lite videos or reading the developer guides linked to in
the instructor notes below. Now before I leave it to Dan
to show you how to implement a sync adapter for
Sunshine that takes advantage of a lot of the best practices
I just described, let's consider what the best practice would be
if you were building something like a news reader app. How
much data should you download when the app is first started?
Just the front page of headlines, all the stories and images
linked to from that front page? Every story available, but none
of the images? Or every story and every image currently available?